export const quiz = {
  totalQuestions: 45,
  questions: [
    {
      id: 1,
      question:
        "Which of the following was one of the earliest counting devices?",
      answers: [
        "A) Napier's Bones",
        "B) Abacus",
        "C) Pascaline",
        "D) Stepped Reckoner",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Abacus",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question: "Who developed Napier's Bones?",
      answers: [
        "A) Blaise Pascal",
        "B) John Napier",
        "C) Charles Babbage",
        "D) Herman Hollerith",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) John Napier",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question:
        "What was significant about Pascaline, invented by Blaise Pascal?",
      answers: [
        "A) It was the first electrical computer",
        "B) It used vacuum tubes",
        "C) It was the first mechanical and automated calculator",
        "D) It could understand natural languages",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) It was the first mechanical and automated calculator",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question:
        "Which device did Wilhelm Leibniz create to improve Pascal's invention?",
      answers: [
        "A) Analytical Engine",
        "B) Difference Engine",
        "C) Stepped Reckoner",
        "D) Tabulating Machine",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Stepped Reckoner",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question:
        "What was the primary function of Charles Babbage's Analytical Engine?",
      answers: [
        "A) To perform basic computations",
        "B) To store data in memory and solve any mathematical problem",
        "C) To multiply and divide using strips marked with numerals",
        "D) To compute statistics and record data",
      ],
      correctAnswer:
        "B) To store data in memory and solve any mathematical problem",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question:
        "Which device did Herman Hollerith invent that later became part of IBM?",
      answers: [
        "A) Mark-I",
        "B) Tabulating Machine",
        "C) Differential Analyzer",
        "D) ENIAC",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Tabulating Machine",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question:
        "What was the Differential Analyzer introduced by Vannevar Bush in 1930?",
      answers: [
        "A) The first digital computer",
        "B) The first electrical computer",
        "C) The first mechanical calculator",
        "D) The first computer to use integrated circuits",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) The first electrical computer",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: "Who invented the Mark-I computer?",
      answers: [
        "A) Howard Aiken",
        "B) Charles Babbage",
        "C) John Napier",
        "D) Vannevar Bush",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "A) Howard Aiken",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question:
        "Which technology characterized the first generation of computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Transistors",
        "B) Integrated Circuits",
        "C) Vacuum Tubes",
        "D) Microprocessors",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Vacuum Tubes",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question:
        "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of first-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Slow processing speed",
        "B) Limited memory capacity",
        "C) Used machine language programming",
        "D) Utilized high-level programming languages",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "D) Utilized high-level programming languages",
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question: "Which of these is an example of a first-generation computer?",
      answers: [
        "A) IBM System/360",
        "B) ENIAC",
        "C) Intel Pentium series",
        "D) CDC 1604",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) ENIAC",
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question: "What replaced vacuum tubes in second-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Microprocessors",
        "B) Transistors",
        "C) Integrated Circuits",
        "D) Optical fibers",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Transistors",
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question:
        "Which high-level programming languages were introduced during the second generation of computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) C++ and Python",
        "B) FORTRAN and COBOL",
        "C) Java and Visual Basic",
        "D) Ruby and Perl",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) FORTRAN and COBOL",
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question:
        "Which of the following is an example of a second-generation computer?",
      answers: [
        "A) IBM 7030",
        "B) Mark-I",
        "C) IBM ThinkPad",
        "D) Analytical Engine",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "A) IBM 7030",
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question:
        "What was the main technological advancement in third-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Vacuum tubes",
        "B) Transistors",
        "C) Microprocessors",
        "D) Integrated Circuits",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "D) Integrated Circuits",
    },
    {
      id: 16,
      question:
        "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of third-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Use of Integrated Circuit chips",
        "B) Energy efficiency and size reduction",
        "C) Capability to concurrently run multiple applications",
        "D) Use of vacuum tubes",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "D) Use of vacuum tubes",
    },
    {
      id: 17,
      question: "Which is an example of a third-generation computer?",
      answers: [
        "A) ENIAC",
        "B) UNIVAC II",
        "C) IBM System/360",
        "D) IBM ThinkPad",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) IBM System/360",
    },
    {
      id: 18,
      question:
        "What marked the defining feature of fourth-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Use of vacuum tubes",
        "B) Introduction of microprocessors",
        "C) Use of transistors",
        "D) Use of integrated circuits",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Introduction of microprocessors",
    },
    {
      id: 19,
      question: "Which is NOT a characteristic of fourth-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Exceptional speed and large storage capacity",
        "B) Use of punched cards for input",
        "C) Operating systems with GUIs",
        "D) Support for multimedia software",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Use of punched cards for input",
    },
    {
      id: 20,
      question:
        "Which of the following is an example of a fourth-generation computer model?",
      answers: [
        "A) Mark-I",
        "B) IBM System/360",
        "C) IBM ThinkPad series",
        "D) ENIAC",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) IBM ThinkPad series",
    },
    {
      id: 21,
      question: "What is the primary focus of fifth-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Use of transistors",
        "B) Use of integrated circuits",
        "C) Development of Artificial Intelligence technologies",
        "D) Introduction of microprocessors",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Development of Artificial Intelligence technologies",
    },
    {
      id: 22,
      question:
        "Which of the following is a characteristic of fifth-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Use of vacuum tubes",
        "B) Advanced parallel processing capabilities",
        "C) Use of punched cards for input",
        "D) Limited memory capacity",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Advanced parallel processing capabilities",
    },
    {
      id: 23,
      question:
        "Which technology is associated with fifth-generation computing?",
      answers: [
        "A) Integrated Circuits",
        "B) Transistors",
        "C) Vacuum tubes",
        "D) Natural Language Processing",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "D) Natural Language Processing",
    },
    {
      id: 24,
      question: "What feature is expected in fifth-generation user interfaces?",
      answers: [
        "A) Punched cards",
        "B) Voice recognition",
        "C) Mechanical switches",
        "D) Electric typewriters",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Voice recognition",
    },
    {
      id: 25,
      question:
        "Which of the following was one of the earliest counting devices, using beads or stones on rods or wires?",
      answers: [
        "A) Napier's Bone",
        "B) Pascaline",
        "C) Abacus",
        "D) Analytical Engine",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Abacus",
    },
    {
      id: 26,
      question:
        "Who invented the mechanical computer that could take input from punch cards?",
      answers: [
        "A) Charles Babbage",
        "B) Blaise Pascal",
        "C) Herman Hollerith",
        "D) John Napier",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "A) Charles Babbage",
    },
    {
      id: 27,
      question:
        "The first electrical computer, using vacuum tubes, was called:",
      answers: [
        "A) Mark I",
        "B) Differential Analyzer",
        "C) Analytical Engine",
        "D) Tabulating Machine",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Differential Analyzer",
    },
    {
      id: 28,
      question:
        "Which component was primarily used in first-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Transistors",
        "B) Vacuum tubes",
        "C) Integrated circuits",
        "D) Microprocessors",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Vacuum tubes",
    },
    {
      id: 29,
      question:
        "The development of which component marked the beginning of the fourth generation of computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Vacuum tubes",
        "B) Transistors",
        "C) Microprocessors",
        "D) Integrated circuits",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Microprocessors",
    },
    {
      id: 30,
      question:
        "Which generation of computers is primarily associated with the development of Artificial Intelligence?",
      answers: ["A) First", "B) Second", "C) Third", "D) Fifth"],
      correctAnswer: "D) Fifth",
    },
    {
      id: 31,
      question:
        "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of second-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Used transistors",
        "B) Smaller and more reliable than first-generation computers",
        "C) Used integrated circuits",
        "D) Introduced high-level programming languages",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Used integrated circuits",
    },
    {
      id: 32,
      question: "What was the primary function of the Analytical Engine?",
      answers: [
        "A) Counting",
        "B) Solving mathematical problems",
        "C) Data storage",
        "D) All of the above",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Solving mathematical problems",
    },
    {
      id: 33,
      question:
        "Who is credited with inventing the tabulating machine, which later became the foundation for IBM?",
      answers: [
        "A) Charles Babbage",
        "B) Herman Hollerith",
        "C) Blaise Pascal",
        "D) John Napier",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Herman Hollerith",
    },
    {
      id: 34,
      question: "What is the main goal of fifth-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Faster processing speed",
        "B) Smaller size",
        "C) Development of Artificial Intelligence",
        "D) Lower cost",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Development of Artificial Intelligence",
    },
    {
      id: 35,
      question:
        "Which device, invented by John Napier, used 9 separate strips for multiplication and division?",
      answers: [
        "A) Abacus",
        "B) Pascaline",
        "C) Napier's Bones",
        "D) Stepped Reckoner",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Napier's Bones",
    },
    {
      id: 36,
      question:
        "Who invented the Differential Analyzer, the first electrical computer?",
      answers: [
        "A) Charles Babbage",
        "B) Howard Aiken",
        "C) Vannevar Bush",
        "D) Herman Hollerith",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Vannevar Bush",
    },
    {
      id: 37,
      question: "The Mark-1 computer, invented by Howard Aiken, could:",
      answers: [
        "A) Add three 8-digit numbers in one second",
        "B) Multiply complex numbers",
        "C) Understand natural language",
        "D) Connect to the internet",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "A) Add three 8-digit numbers in one second",
    },
    {
      id: 38,
      question:
        "Which generation of computers first introduced the use of assembly language?",
      answers: [
        "A) First Generation",
        "B) Second Generation",
        "C) Third Generation",
        "D) Fourth Generation",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Second Generation",
    },
    {
      id: 39,
      question:
        "What was a significant advancement in the second generation of computers compared to the first?",
      answers: [
        "A) Introduction of vacuum tubes",
        "B) Use of punch cards for input",
        "C) Replacement of vacuum tubes with transistors",
        "D) Development of artificial intelligence",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Replacement of vacuum tubes with transistors",
    },
    {
      id: 40,
      question:
        "Which of the following was one of the earliest counting devices, using beads or stones on rods or wires?",
      answers: [
        "A) Napier's Bone",
        "B) Pascaline",
        "C) Abacus",
        "D) Analytical Engine",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Abacus",
    },
    {
      id: 41,
      question:
        "Who invented the mechanical computer that could take input from punch cards?",
      answers: [
        "A) Charles Babbage",
        "B) Blaise Pascal",
        "C) Herman Hollerith",
        "D) John Napier",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "A) Charles Babbage",
    },
    {
      id: 42,
      question:
        "The first electrical computer, using vacuum tubes, was called:",
      answers: [
        "A) Mark I",
        "B) Differential Analyzer",
        "C) Analytical Engine",
        "D) Tabulating Machine",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Differential Analyzer",
    },
    {
      id: 43,
      question:
        "Which component was primarily used in first-generation computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Transistors",
        "B) Vacuum tubes",
        "C) Integrated circuits",
        "D) Microprocessors",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "B) Vacuum tubes",
    },
    {
      id: 44,
      question:
        "The development of which component marked the beginning of the fourth generation of computers?",
      answers: [
        "A) Vacuum tubes",
        "B) Transistors",
        "C) Microprocessors",
        "D) Integrated circuits",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "C) Microprocessors",
    },
    {
      id: 45,
      question:
        "Which generation of computers is primarily associated with the development of Artificial Intelligence?",
      answers: ["A) First", "B) Second", "C) Third", "D) Fifth"],
      correctAnswer: "D) Fifth",
    },
  ],
};
